

Summary

I am an experienced Childcare Worker with an excellent history of working in the non-profit industry. I previously attended and graduated from Penn State University in 2007 where I majored in Information Science and Technology. There I learned how to code in C++ and Javascript; how to write HTML, XML and CSS; and last but not least the importance of a good UX/UI. In May of 2019 I completed a Udemy online course, *The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery,* which taught front-end and back-end development. My skills are in Express.js, Node.js, React.js, Javascript, HTML, and CSS. My goal is to further hone my problem-solving and analytical skills as they will help me to write and debug code better. I look forward to joining a company in which I can become a valuable asset and contributing member to a team.

Technical Skills

- Web Technologies: Javascript, React.js, Express.js, Node.js, HTML,
 CSS
- Databases: Postgres, MySQL
- Cloud: GIT, GITHUB, Heroku cloud (Dynos, Postgres)

Experience

Oct 2011 - present

Childcare/Mental Health Worker

Silver Springs/Martin Luther School, Plymouth Meeting, PA

- Organize educational activities during the day for kids who have not yet started school.
- Supervise a pleasant wake-up routine for all children on the residential unit.
- Communicate health needs or concerns to the nurse and/or Executive-On-Duty (EOD).
- Tolerate behavior that is defiant and aggressive. Use SCM techniques (may include physical redirection and passive physical restraint) when situations warrant in accordance with SS/MLS policies, procedures and applicable Commonwealth regulations.
- Communicate with other departments as necessary (i.e. Health Care, Food Service, Martin Luther School, etc.).
- Maintain strict confidentiality, as required by Commonwealth regulations, law and SS/MLS policies.

Jun 2007 -Jun 2010

Field Technician

Comcast, Philadelphia, PA

- Provides tech support for all equipment installed at customers' residences
- Performs custom installation work including wall fishing, post



Address

240 West Walnut Lane Apt. C300 Philadelphia, PA 19144

Phone

267-880-8942

E-mail

yujirojenkins@gmail.com

Date of birth

May 09, 1985

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ty-jenkins/

GitHub

https://github.com/Yujiman85

WWW

https://yujiman85.github.io/

Facebook

www.facebook.com/Ty-Yuji

Instagram

www.instagram.com/spacemanci

wiring, etc.

- Ensures all jobs are completed as instructed by customers' demands
- Manages issues and resolutions in a timely manner

Jun 2005 -Jun 2007

Head of IT

Global Construction Technologies Inc., Philadelphia, PA

- Coordinates IT operations for company
- Implements remedial processes to help improve business functions



Education

Jan 2018 -May 2019

The Complete Web Developer in 2019: Zero to Mastery, Udemy Online Course

- Taught skills in Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, HTML, and CSS
- Coursework in both front-end and back-end development
- Problem-solving and debugging

Sep 2003 -May 2007

Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA

- B.S. in Information Science and Technology
- Focus on Integration and Application



Citizenship



United States



Projects

Smart Brain (Face Recognition Web App)

An app created using React. It takes an image uploaded by the user and detects whether there is a face present. If so, the app will put a bounding box around the face. The app can also detect multiple faces and will display the appropriate amount of bounding boxes.

- Created the various components used in the UI using a combination of JSX and CSS.
- Used Javascript to create the functionality for each component.
- Coded the back end using Node, Express and various middleware (bodyparser and cors).
- Used knex to connect back-end to a Postgres database where users are stored and bcrypt to hash users' passwords.
- Connected front- and back-end so users can create a profile which is stored so they can later sign back in.

Robo Friends

A simple react app that fetches JSON objects (the robots) and displays their picture and name on cards. The app uses state to actively search through the objects when the user is typing a name into the search bar.

- Coded using React and JSX.
- Uses state to make the app more interactive when searching through robots.

Background Gradient Generator

A single HTML page with a button that generates two random colors, then sets the first and second color as the background gradient from left to right, respectively.

- Created an HTML Page that, on load, generates a random gradient consisting of two colors.
- Used javascript to create functions to generate two random colors on button press and set those colors as the background gradient for the page.

References

References available upon request